AULIA KHOIRUNNISA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Mathematics graduate with 4 years of experience analyzing quantitative and qualitative data on money laundering research in Pusat Pelaporan dan Analisis Transaksi Keuangan (Indonesian Financial Intelligence Unit). Eager to enhance expertise and insight in advanced data and analytics skills to keep pace with the massive data onboarding especially financial transaction data.

WORK HISTORY

Financial Transaction Analyst - Researcher, 01/2019 to Current Pusat Pelaporan dan Analis Transaksi Keuangan (PPATK) - Jakarta

- Spearheaded comprehensive evaluations of PPATK's yearly operational performance by gathering and analyzing feedback from a diverse range of stakeholders, including financial institutions, regulatory bodies, law enforcement agencies, and foreign Financial Intelligence Units (FIUs), to enhance strategic oversight and operational effectiveness.
- Conducted thorough investigations into PPATK's internal systems to identify and document security loopholes and operational inefficiencies.
- Led the development and implementation of risk assessment frameworks to analyze and mitigate the threats of money laundering at sectoral, national, and transnational levels.
- Managed the compilation and dissemination of detailed statistical bulletins on money laundering trends which served as a key informational resource for stakeholders within and outside PPATK, informing them about current trends and enabling data-driven decision-making to combat money laundering effectively.

Actuarial Funding Analyst, 01/2017 to 12/2018 PT. ASABRI (Persero) - Jakarta

- Spearheaded the evaluation of the company's short-term and long-term financial health. Utilized quantitative techniques to analyze cash flow, asset management, and debt structures, ensuring strategic alignment with corporate financial goals.
- Supported actuarial functions by applying mathematical and statistical methods to assess risk and determine insurance premiums and reserves. Utilized analytical skills to contribute to the development of pricing strategies and risk evaluation models.
- Ensured compliance with financial regulations by preparing detailed reports for oversight bodies. Produced financial status reports demonstrating adherence to statutory requirements.
- Successfully passed 4 out of 7 modules of the Associate of Society of Actuaries of Indonesia, demonstrating a high level of proficiency and commitment to actuarial standards and practices.

University Teaching Assistant, 09/2014 to 12/2017 Institut Pertanian Bogor (IPB) University - Bogor

Assist the professor in preparing for lectures and presentations. This
may involve gathering necessary materials, setting up equipment, or

CONTACT

Address: Perumahan Poin Mas Blok K3

Mampang, Depok, Indonesia **Phone:** (+62)822-1354-0577

Email: auliakhoirunnisa@outlook.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/aulia-khoirun

nisa-91b566132

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

The Best Graduate of Mathematics Department on Sept, 2016

SEVERAL PUBLICATIONS

- Penilaian Risiko Sektoral Tindak Pidana Pencucian Uang Pada Tindak Pidana Penipuan SIBER Tahun 2022 (Sectoral Risk Assessment on Cyber Fraud) (2022)
 https://www.ppatk.go.id/publikasi /read/165/penilaian-risiko-sektoraltindak-pidana-pencucian-uang-padatindak-pidana-penipuan-siber-tahun-2022.html
- Riset Tipologi Tahun 2021: Berdasarkan Putusan Pengadilan Pencucian Uang Tahun 2020 (Typology Research for 2021: Based on the 2020 Money Laundering Court Decision) (2022) https://www.ppatk.go.id/publikasi /read/160/riset-tipologi-tahun-2021-berdasarkan-putusanpengadilan-pencucian-uang-tahun-2020.html
- Buletin Statistik Anti Pencucian Uang dan Pencegahan Pendanaan Terorisme (Statistics Bulletin on Money Laundering) (2021 - 2022) https://www.ppatk.go.id/link/read /1249/buletin-statistik-apu-ppt.html
- Red Flag Indicators of Transnational Laundering of Corruption Proceeds (2021)
- Analisis Bifurkasi Hopf Dinamika Harga pada Model Ekonomi dengan Dua Waktu Tunda (Hopf Bifurcation Analysis of Price Dynamics on Economic Model with Two Time Delays) (2016) https://repository.ipb.ac.id/handle /123456789/85821

- organizing digital resources.
- Leading smaller, supplementary class sessions or tutorials to reinforce lecture materials, clarify complex topics, and provide additional examples.
- Managing the classroom dynamics during the professor's lectures, such as tracking attendance, facilitating group activities, and maintaining a conducive learning environment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Mathematics - Distinction, 09/2012 to 07/2016 Institut Pertanian Bogor (IPB University) - Bogor

GPA: 3.97 out of 4.00

Expertise in Calculus, Linear Algebra, Discrete Mathematics, Algebra Structure, Introduction to Probability Theory, and Computation Method.

Master of Science, Data Analytics, 09/2023 - Current University of Glasgow - Glasgow

- Coursework in Data Analytics of University of Glasgow
- Statistical Programming (R Studio & Python), Probability, Inference Statistics, Database Theory and Analytics, Regression Models, Big Data Analytics, Functional Data Analytics, Data Mining & Machine Learning, Bayesian Statistics, Advanced Predictive Models, and Data Analytics Skills. It will be closed with a Capstone Project and Dissertation.

REFERENCES

- Beren Rukur Ginting, Director of Analysis and Investigation One - Pusat Pelaporan dan Analisis Transaksi Keuangan Indonesia (beren.rukur@ppatk.go.id)
- Yudi Aditia, Group Coordinator of Reporting Institutions Integrity
 Assessment, Management of Data, Information and Statistics - Pusat Pelaporan dan Analisis Transaksi Keuangan Indonesia (yudi.aditia@ppatk.go.id)